(Applause)
(تصفيق)
It's really quite an honor to be here tonight,
أنه لشرف لي أن أكون هنا الليلة،
and I'm really glad that I stayed here and listened
وأنا سعيد حقاُ إنني إنتظرت هنا وإستمعت
because I've really been inspired.
لأني حقاُ أُلهمت.
And I'm going to play some songs for you tonight
وسوف أعزف بعض الأغاني لكم الليلة
that are, literally, world premieres.
وهي عن حق تعزف لأول مرة في العالم.
I've been working on my new record
لقد كنت أعمل لأصدار ألبومي الجديد
and I've never played these songs for anybody
ولم أعزف هذه الأغاني لأي احد من قبل
except the microphone.
بإستثناء الميكروفون.
This is a song that I wrote
هذه أغنية كتبتها
about the meaning of technology,
عن معني التكنولوجيا،
which goes perfectly with this gathering.
وهي تتماشي مع هذا الجمع.
I started thinking about -- when I was in college,
بدأت التفكير فيها عندما كنت في الكلية،
especially as a blind person,
خاصة كشخص كفيف،
doing a research paper was a major undertaking.
القيام بعمل بحث كان مهمة كبيرة.
You had to go to the library,
كان ينبغي الذهاب للمكتبة،
see if you could get them to find the books for you,
لتري إن كان بإستطاعتك جعلهم يجدون الكتب من اجلك،
you know, footnotes and all that.
كما تعرفون، الحواشي وكل ذلك.
Now you can just go on Google. Just look it up.
الأن يمكنك الدخول لجوجل. والبحث عنهم.
I wish I had that when I was in college.
كنتت أتمني لو كان لدي هذا عندما كنت في الكلية.
Anyway, this is a song about:
علي أية حال، هذه أغنية عن --
we have all this, but what are we going to do with it?
لدينا كل هذا، لكن ماذا سوف نفعل به؟
It's called "All the Answers."
أسمها "كل الحلول."
♫ What is the weather in Cincinnati? ♫
♫ما حال الطقس في سينسيناتي؟♫
♫ What is the time in Tokyo? ♫
♫ما هو الوقت في طوكيو؟♫
♫ Who is this little child's daddy? ♫
♫من والد هذا الطفل الصغير؟♫
♫ And who the hell needs to know? ♫
♫ومن يريد أن يعرف؟♫
♫ Why do memories of you linger ♫
♫ولما ذكراك مازالت باقية♫
♫ when I'm trying to reach my goal? ♫
♫ عندما أحاول الوصول إلى هدفي؟ ♫
♫ And why must I move my fingers ♫
♫ ولماذا يجب أن أحرك أصابعي ♫
♫ to the music in my soul? ♫
♫ للموسيقى في روحي؟ ♫
♫ I don't know. ♫
♫ لا أعرف ♫
♫ I don't have to know. ♫
♫ولست مضطراً لإعرف ♫
♫ 'Cause here I go ... ♫
♫ لأني سأبدأ ... ♫
♫ and I got all the answers ♫
♫ ولدي كل الإجابات ♫
♫ right here in my hand. ♫
♫ هنا في يدي ♫
♫ and I don't have to understand ♫
♫ ولست مضطراً أن أفهم ♫
♫ 'cause I got all the answers. ♫
♫ لأن لدي كل الإجابات ♫
♫ Think I'll rummage through the century ♫
♫ أعتقد أنني سوف أبحث في عجالة خلال القرن ♫
♫ while I listen to the sea. ♫
♫ بينما أستمع إلى البحر ♫
♫ Oh, it's good to be so free, ♫
♫ أوه ، إنه من الجيد أن أكون حراً جداً ♫
♫ so free. ♫
♫ حراً جداً ♫
♫ Who was mayor of Chicago ♫
♫ من كان عمدة شيكاغو ♫
♫ back in 1964? ♫
♫ في عام 1964؟♫
♫ And why did Shakespeare create Iago ♫
♫ ولماذا أبتكر شكسبير ياجو ♫
♫ to tear apart a love so pure? ♫
♫ لبمزق حب نقي إلى هذا الحد؟ ♫
♫ How can my dreams be so vivid ♫
♫ كيف يمكن أن تكون أحلامي بهذا الوضوح ♫
♫ in a psychosonic way? ♫
♫ في شكل صوت عقلي؟♫
♫ Why must I become so livid ♫
♫ لماذا يجب ان أغضب جدا ♫
♫ about the news I hear today? ♫
♫ بخصوص الأخبار التي أتتني اليوم؟ ♫
♫ I don't know. ♫
♫ لا أعرف ♫
♫ I don't have to know. ♫
♫ولست مضطراً لإعرف ♫
♫ And here I go ... ♫
♫ وها أنا ذا♫
♫ 'cause I got all the answers ♫
♫ لأن لدي كل الإجابات ♫
♫ right here in my hand. ♫
♫ هنا في يدي ♫
♫ And I got all the answers. ♫
♫ ولدي كل الإجابات ♫
♫ See, I don't have to understand ♫
♫ أتري، لست مضطراً أن أفهم ♫
♫ 'cause I got all the answers. ♫
♫ لأن لدي كل الإجابات ♫
♫ I think I'll browse on through ♫
♫ أعتقد أني سأتصفح ♫
♫ the tabloid news ♫
♫ صحف الأخبار غير المهمة ♫
♫ while I sip my tea. ♫
♫ بينما أرتشف الشاي ♫
♫ Mm, it's good to be so free. ♫
♫ مم ، أنه من الجيد أن تكون بهذه الحرية ♫
(Trumpet sounds)
(أصوات الترومبت)
♫ I never ever have to be alone. ♫
♫ لن أكون أبداً مضطراً أن أكون وحيداً ♫
♫ I can do it all right here in my home. ♫
♫ أستطيع أن أفعل كل شيء هنا في بيتي ♫
♫ Yeah, mm-hmm ... ♫
♫ نعم ، ممم هممم... ♫
♫ Everything that's ever been known, ♫
♫ كل شيء عرف علي الاطلاق ♫
♫ I can punch it up right here on my phone. ♫
♫ يمكنني طلبها علي تليفوني ♫
♫ Freedom train, coming soon ♫
♫ قطار الحرية، قادم قريباً ♫
♫ right here in my living room ♫
♫ هنا في حجرة معيشتي ♫
♫ from Baton Rouge to Saskatoon ♫
♫ من باتون روج إلي ساسكتون ♫
♫ and all points in between. ♫
♫ وكل ما بينهما ♫
♫ 'Cause I got all the answers ♫
♫ لأن لدي كل الإجابات ♫
♫ right here on my screen. ♫
♫ هنا علي شاشتي ♫
♫ And I got all the answers, yeah. ♫
♫ و لدي كل الإجابات، نعم ♫
♫ I got every book and magazine. ♫
♫ لدي كل الكتب والمجلات ♫
♫ I got all, I got all, I got all ... ♫
♫ لدي جميعها، لدي جميعها، لدي جميعها ..♫
♫ I got all the answers, ♫
♫ لدي كل الإجابات ♫
♫ all the answers, oh yeah. ♫
♫ لدي كل الإجابات، أي نعم ♫
♫ Uh-huh ... ♫
♫أهـ ها....♫
♫ But I tell you what I'm going to do: ♫
♫ لكن سأقول لكم ما سوف أفعله ♫
♫ I'm going to find the capitol of Peru ♫
♫ سأعرف عاصمة بيرو♫
♫ or the latitude of Kathmandu. ♫
♫أو مكان كاتماندو♫
♫ I'm gonna Google it ♫
♫سأبحث عنها في جوجل♫
♫ 'cause everybody's doing it. ♫
♫ لأن الجميع يفعل ذلك ♫
♫ And then I'll rummage through the century. ♫
♫ وعندها سوف أبحث في عجالة خلال القرن ♫
♫ I got all, I got all, I got all ... ♫
♫ لدي كل شيء، لدي كل شيء، لدي كل شيء...♫
♫ I got all the answers. ♫
♫ لدي كل الإجابات ♫
♫ Yeah, yeah ♫
♫ نعم، نعم ♫
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
Whew! It's a miracle I didn't make any mistakes on that song.
واو! إنها لمعجزة إني لم أخطيء في الأغنية.
That's the first time I've ever played it.
هذه أول مرة أعزفها.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
It's a "feel the fear and do it anyway" kind of thing.
♫أنها من نوع "أشعر بالخوف ولكن أفعلها علي أية حال"♫
This next song is a song
الأغنية القادمة هي أغنية
that started out as a dream -- a childhood dream.
بدأت كحلم -- حلم طفولة.
It was one of the titles
كانت أحد العناوين
that I was sort of thinking about calling my record,
التي كنت أفكر في تسمية ألبومي بها
except there's a couple of problems.
إلا أنه كانت هناك مشكلتين.
One thing is, it's unpronounceable.
أحدهما صعوبة نطقها.
And it's a made-up word.
وأنها كلمة مختلقة.
It's called "Tembererana."
إنها تسمي "تمبريرانا."
And the song is based on
والأغنية مبنية علي
what I think was my first
ما أعتقد انه أولى
childhood attempts
محاولات الطفولة
to think about invisible forces.
للتفكير في القوي غير المرئية.
So "tembererana" was these dreams,
إذن "تمبريرانا" كانت هي هذه الأحلام..
in which I would be running away
التي فيها أهرب
from bad feelings -- is the only way I can put it.
من الأحاسيس السيئة -- هذه أفضل طريقة لوصفها.
So this is called "Tembererana."
إذن هذه تسمي "تمبريرانا."
It's based on an Argentinian rhythm
أنها مبنية علي إيقاع أرجنتيني
called "carnivalito."
يسمي كارنيفاليتو.
♫ A dream within a dream, ♫
♫ حلم داخل حلم ♫
♫ a world within a world, ♫
♫ عالم داخل عالم ♫
♫ the sound of a primal scream ♫
♫ صوت صرخة بدائية ♫
♫ travels out across the land. ♫
♫ يسافر عبر الأرض ♫
♫ Images flickering, ♫
♫ صور تومض وتخبو♫
♫ the sound of the war machine, ♫
♫ صوت ألة الحرب ♫
♫ a procession of limousines ♫
♫ موكب من السيارات الفاخرة ♫
♫ travels slowly across the land. ♫
♫ يتهادي عبر الأرض ♫
♫ Another child could use a hand. ♫
♫ طفل أخر يحتاج المساعدة ♫
♫ Reaching out from within ♫
♫ يتواصل من الداخل ♫
♫ tembererana, hey, tembererana ... ♫
♫ تمبريرانا، هيي ، تمبريرانا...♫
♫ Annihilation moves. ♫
♫ الابادة التحركات♫
♫ The earth is an open tomb. ♫
♫ الأرض قبر مفتوح ♫
♫ The sound of the final boom ♫
♫ صوت الإنفجار الأخير ♫
♫ rumbles fiercely across the land. ♫
♫ يدوي بشدة في جميع أنحاء الأرض ♫
♫ Fear, you're the enemy. ♫
♫ الخوف ، أنت العدو ♫
♫ Obliterating all but thee. ♫
♫ تطمس كل شيء إلا نفسك ♫
♫ You see what you want to see. ♫
♫ تري ما تريد أن تري ♫
♫ Before I'm blinded, I will toast ♫
♫ قبل أن أعمي سوف أقوم بنخب ♫
♫ the shade of power that I love most, ♫
♫ ظل القوة التي أحبها أكثر من أي شيء ♫
♫ the power of creation. ♫
♫ قوة الإبداع ♫
♫ Tembererana, hey, tembererana ... ♫
♫ تمبريرانا، هيي ، تمبريرانا...♫
♫ Da, da, da, da ♫
♫ دا، دا، دا، دا ♫
♫ Da, da, da, da, da, da, da ♫
♫ دا، دا، دا، دا، دا، دا، دا ♫
♫ As a child, alone and afraid, ♫
♫ كطفل وحيد وخائف ♫
♫ escaping the impressions every feeling made, ♫
♫ أهرب من الأثار التي سببتها هذه الأحاسيس ♫
♫ I would run, run away ♫
♫ سوف أهرب، أهرب بعيداً ♫
♫ into a world where the good was the aim of the game ♫
♫ لعالم فيه الخير كان هو الهدف من اللعبة ♫
♫ and the sum of invisible power ♫
♫ ومحصلة القوي غير المرئية ♫
♫ had a name. ♫
♫ كان لها إسم ♫
♫ It's the same name. ♫
♫ إنه نفس الشيء... ♫
♫ Tembererana, hey, tembererana ... ♫
♫ تمبريرانا، هيي ، تمبريرانا...♫
♫ Da, da, da, da, da, da, da ♫
♫ دا، دا، دا، دا، دا، دا، دا ♫
♫ Tembere, tembere, tembere, tembererana ♫
♫ تمبر، تمبر، تمبر، تمبريرانا ♫
♫ Tembere, tembere, tembere, tembererana, hey ♫
♫ تمبر، تمبر، تمبر، تمبريرانا، هيي ♫
♫ Tembererana, hey ♫
♫ تمبريرانا، هيي ♫
♫ Tembererana ... ♫
♫ تمبريرانا... ♫
(Applause)
(تصفيق)